<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Classes>
  <Class>
    <Key>LOW</Key>
    <Name>The Down and Out</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Down and Out[h4]
      Please see page 36 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="36">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="36">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
  </Class>
  <Class>
    <Key>MIDDLE</Key>
    <Name>Middle Class Struggles</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Middle Class Struggles[h4]
      Please see page 37 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
  </Class>
  <Class>
    <Key>HIGH</Key>
    <Name>The High and Mighty</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The High and Mighty[h4]
      Please see page 37 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
  </Class>
  <Class>
    <Key>OUT</Key>
    <Name>The Outsider</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Outsider[h4]
      Please see page 37 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="37">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
  </Class>
  <Class>
    <Key>COMFBEN</Key>
    <Name>Comfortable Beneficiaries</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Comfortable Beneficiaries[h4]
      Senator Palpatine's rise to power was no accident. He
engineered matters expertly to capitalize on the desire
of civilized people for law and order, peace, and security.
The events of the Separatist movement and the
subsequent Clone Wars, coupled with the apparent (and
well-publicized) degradation of the Jedi and their inability
to do anything about the ensuing chaos, provided a
powerful platform upon which to sell the Republic on
the need for firm measures to restore order.
This could not have happened if many billions of
beings weren't willing participants in the transition. The
restoration of order by the central government meant
a return to relative normalcy: business resuming,
unimpeded shipping, threats of violence and destruction
removed. For the majority of those living in the
Core Worlds and related systems, this is a preferable
state of affairs, no matter who is in charge or how they
go about implementing their authority. If it is no longer
politically or socially wise to complain about the
government too loudly, so be it—dinner still gets on
the table, the holovid still shows great and entertaining
programs, and the average person is generally left
alone to lead his life in relative peace.
Many who join the Rebellion come from such circumstances.
They join not because their lives are filled with
misery or tragedy, but because they grasp the insidious
nature of the powers that have taken control. They
have a deeper understanding of how much is being
lost, surreptitiously stripped away day by day while no
one seems to notice or care. Such PCs may be idealists
seeking to awaken their fellow citizens before it's too
late and everything is lost to the corruption of Palpatine's
absolute power. They may be malcontents who
have been rejected by their families and local society
for daring to speak out against the injustices others are
suffering in the name of their own peace and security.
Such PCs might never have intended to become
caught up in any resistance against the New Order.
Rather, a series of incidents could have led them accidentally
(yet inexorably) toward a point of conflict with
Imperial forces, driving them straight into the arms of
the only people who can help them: the Rebellion.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="43">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Class>
  <Class>
    <Key>VISOPP</Key>
    <Name>Visionary Opportunists</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Visionary Opportunists[h4]
      Conflict brings change, and change brings opportunity.
Many in the galaxy are unsatisfied with the status
quo—especially as it exists under Palpatine's rule. The
Alliance's war against the Empire provides an extraordinary
chance to topple the current order and bring
about more desirable changes. Whether those changes
are oriented toward reestablishing the Republic as it
was or installing a new structure altogether depends on
the individual's frame of mind.
Many who seek such change are genuinely altruistic
in their goals. They recognize the evil of the Empire and
the suffering it brings. They're motivated to end this
evil, and the Rebellion's organization and resources
offer the best possibility of accomplishing their goal.
Whether they join the Rebellion simply because they
were made aware of Imperial atrocities and destruc-
CHARACTER CREATION
ACE OF REBELLION
tive policies, or because they and their loved ones have
been directly victimized by the Empire, is for the players
to decide.
Others have less idealistic, perhaps even selfish,
goals. Current policies might cut into their ability to
make a profit in their chosen vocation or damage the
business they choose to run. Perhaps a character has
run afoul of Imperial authorities one too many times,
and he sees an alliance with the Rebellion as his best
chance of escaping the less-than-tender mercies of the
Empire's justice. Some PCs may simply see a chance to
grab some credits and valuable assets while helping to
strike against the Empire's forces.
A technician or engineer could have had his designs
rejected by Imperial agents, and the Alliance is providing
him a chance to vindicate his work. A politician or
political operative might have been ousted when the
current regime took power; the Rebellion provides an
opportunity to reclaim a sense of purpose and authority.
A pilot deemed unfit for service and rejected by
the Imperial Academy would consider flying for the
Alliance a chance to prove his worth at the controls of
a starhghter.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="43">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Class>
  <Class>
    <Key>JUSTAV</Key>
    <Name>Justified Avengers</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Justified Avengers[h4]
      The Alliance to Restore the Republic may exist for the
sake of undoing the terrible mistake of allowing Palpatine's
rise to power, but the Rebellion is sustained on
the backs of those who seek to overthrow the Empire
because of the evil it has wrought across the galaxy.
Millions—perhaps billions by now—have already died
or suffered horribly under its harsh rule, and a huge
portion of the rank-and-file among the Alliance's forces
come from families, planets, and even entire systems
that have been victimized.
The Empire's "pro-human" philosophy is perhaps one
of the greatest propaganda tools the Alliance enjoys.
Species that have known respect and admiration for
their contributions to galactic civilization for millennia
now find themselves marginalized. Their people
second-class citizens of the Empire at best, and slaves
all too often, more and more of the governments representing
these species are throwing in their lot with
the Alliance. These beings bring with them their skills,
talents, resources, and passionate desire to live peacefully
with their fellow sentients throughout the galaxy
to the battle against Emperor Palpatine's "humans
first" policies.
The war machine of the Empire is voracious in its
hunger, and those who seek to feed it have little or
no compulsion against using wide-scale slave labor to
obtain the resources and build the countless machines
it needs. Entire planets and civilizations have suffered
the fate of Kashyyyk and its indigenous Wookiees,
enslaved en masse by the Empire and put to work. Individuals
who have managed to avoid capture, or who
are rescued by others, often sign on with the Alliance
for the chance to strike back and, perhaps one day,
free their people. Not surprisingly, the Alliance goes
out of its way to free such beings whenever possible.
Death and destruction are also frequent tools
employed by Imperial forces for the sake of enforcing
order and the Emperor's will. Any signs of opposition
are usually answered with arrests, followed by banishment
to distant prisons and labor camps, or outright
executions. On grander scales, the Emperor employs
overwhelming assault forces or orbital bombardment.
Emperor Palpatine is satisfied to rule by fear, ensuring
that dozens of planets within a sector bow to his
will with the utter destruction of one. While this strategy
keeps many systems in line, those that survive his
reprisals almost invariably sign on with the Rebellion
for a chance to strike back on behalf of the many who
have been lost.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="44">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Class>
  <Class>
    <Key>COMFTECH</Key>
    <Name>Comfortable with Tech</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Comfortable with Tech[h4]
      Please see page 45 of the Force and Destiny Core Rulebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="45">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Class>
  <Class>
    <Key>PRIMBACK</Key>
    <Name>Primitive Backwater</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Primitive Backwater[h4]
      Please see page 45 of the Force and Destiny Core Rulebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="45">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Class>
  <Class>
    <Key>PRIVFEW</Key>
    <Name>The Privileged Few</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Privileged Few[h4]
      Please see page 45 of the Force and Destiny Core Rulebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="45">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Class>
  <Class>
    <Key>POORHUNG</Key>
    <Name>The Poor and Hungry</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]The Poor and Hungry[h4]
      Please see page 46 of the Force and Destiny Core Rulebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="46">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Class>
</Classes>
