<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Duties>
  <Duty>
    <Key>COMBATVICTORY</Key>
    <Name>Combat Victory</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Combat Victory[h4]
      The Player Character is driven to show that the Alliance can hold its own against Imperial forces in any
troop vs. troop engagement. He wants to engage the Empire's military—their best, whenever possible—and provide more
victories for the Alliance to tout to the galaxy as proof it can ultimately win the war. This means daring raids, excellent
tactics, and acquiring the best firepower possible.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>COUNTERINTELLIGENCE</Key>
    <Name>Counter Intelligence</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Counter Intelligence[h4]
      The PC knows that the survival of the Alliance depends upon its ability to hide from the Empire
and avoid complete destruction at the hands of its overwhelming military superiority. To this end. he wants to hunt
down and eliminate enemy agents and threats, feed false information to Imperial intelligence networks, and cover the
movements of all Alliance assets from observation and reporting
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>INTELLIGENCE</Key>
    <Name>Intelligence</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Intelligence[h4]
      The PC knows that every victory hinges on knowing as much about the Empire's military might and other
assets as possible. He is driven to gather any and all potentially useful data, wishing to locate vital and vulnerable targets
for Rebellion forces to strike at. He not only wants to know what the Imperial military factions are up to. but also the
state of technological research, economic policies, and other aspects of Imperial strength.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>INTERNALSECURITY</Key>
    <Name>Internal Security</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Internal Security[h4]
      The most dangerous threat to the Alliance comes from within its own ranks. Any Rebel soldier,
operative, or ally could be an insidious threat waiting to take an action at a critical moment to bring entire operations
crashing down, costing lives and assets. Knowing that vigilance against these threats is the truest form of devotion to the
cause of the Alliance, the PC watches for any and all signs of betrayal.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>PERSONNEL</Key>
    <Name>Personnel</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Personnel[h4]
      More than machines, credits, or information, the people of the Alliance are the most important and vital
assets there are, and the Player Character knows this. He is devoted to seeing to their safety, well-being, and capacity
for success. No one should ever be left behind: the most successful missions might not achieve every goal, but they are
successful nonetheless when no one dies.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>POLITICALSUPPORT</Key>
    <Name>Political Support</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Political Support[h4]
      Every blaster, starhghter, and thermal detonator in the galaxy is useless without the political will to
truly challenge and overthrow Palpatine and his New Order The Player Character understands this all too well and is
determined to see to it that as many factions, systems, and sectors as possible come to the side—and the aid—of the
Alliance against the Empire.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>RECRUITING</Key>
    <Name>Recruiting</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Recruiting[h4]
      Every engagement with the Empire is a war o f attrition, and that is a war the Rebellion simply cannot win.
Nonetheless, more people must be found to serve, and they are needed in every capacity. Not only does the Alliance
military need more soldiers and pilots, it needs more technicians, engineers, mechanics, scientists, doctors, slicers, and
just about every other kind of worker. This Player Character understands the risks of recruitment, as well as the needs,
and is constantly on the lookout for allies who are both talented and trustworthy.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>RESOURCEACQUISITION</Key>
    <Name>Resource Acquisition</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Resource Acquisition[h4]
      There are never enough supplies to fully support those fighting against the juggernaut that is
the Empire, and this PC knows it very well. He is determined to seek out new sources of raw materials, food, clothing,
weapons, armor, and equipment of all kinds. One spare crate of medpacs can save quite a few lives, and a handful
of comlinks can mean the difference between success and failure on a mission. He will trade, beg. borrow, and steal
anything for the cause.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>SABOTAGE</Key>
    <Name>Sabotage</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Sabotage[h4]
      The largest and most powerful military force in the history of the galaxy is also the most vulnerable to acts of
destruction and asset denial. The character is focused on disrupting Imperial operations in any way possible, whether it's
the manufacture of weapons, troop movements, supply shipments, banking systems, or any other key operation, in order
to make the Empire act more slowly and less capably. Truly showy acts of destruction also work to erode a population's
will to support the Empire, or so the PC often believes (though the Alliance expressly forbids actual acts of terrorism).
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>SPACESUPERIORITY</Key>
    <Name>Space Superiority</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Space Superiority[h4]
      As the Combat Victory-driven PC feels about troop conflicts, so this Player Character feels about
ship-to-ship combat and naval engagements. To him, the war will ultimately be decided in the stars, and what the Alliance
lacks in sheer numbers, it more than makes up for in the quality and tenacity of its pilots. Every single space battle is an
opportunity to show the rest of the galaxy that the Alliance not only can win the war, but is destined to do so
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>TECHPROCUREMENT</Key>
    <Name>Tech Procurement</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Tech Procurement[h4]
      There is no more prolific or productive time for technological developments than during a war, and
this one is no exception. This Player Character sees the true opportunity for Alliance victory in the hands of scientists,
engineers, and technicians. Not only can they get the most performance from existing machines and resources, but
they can design and develop new ships, weapons, medical techniques, and equipment that can provide the vital edge
necessary to survive against the Empire's might. The way this PC sees it, stealing the best developments of the Empire is
a crucial way to even the odds.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>SUPPORT</Key>
    <Name>Support</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Support[h4]
      Individually, the lone agents of the Alliance don't stand a chance against the combined might of the Galactic
Empire. Only by working together can they hope to achieve a victory in this civil war. This PC is devoted to helping fellow
Rebels fulfill their Duties by providing whatever assistance they need. Although he might not get the same amount of
reward or recognition as the people he is helping, the PC has many more opportunities than his fellows to fulfill his Duty
to the Rebellion.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="47">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>AIRSUP</Key>
    <Name>Air Superiority</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Air Superiority[h4]
      Please see page 19 of the Stay on Target Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="19">Stay on Target</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>GROUNDSUP</Key>
    <Name>Ground Superiority</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Ground Superiority[h4]
      Please see page 19 of the Stay on Target Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="19">Stay on Target</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>PLACHUNT</Key>
    <Name>Placard Hunter</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Placard Hunter[h4]
      Please see page 19 of the Stay on Target Sourcebook, or page 17 of the Forged in Battle Sourcebook, for details.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="19">Stay on Target</Source>
      <Source Page="17">Forged in Battle</Source>
    </Sources>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>TECHSUPERIORITY</Key>
    <Name>Tech Superiority</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Tech Superiority[h4]
      Please see page 19 of the Stay on Target Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="19">Stay on Target</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>COMMFAC</Key>
    <Name>Communication Facilitation</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Communication Facilitation[h4]
      Please see page 17 of the Desperate Allies Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="17">Desperate Allies</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>OPPLAN</Key>
    <Name>Operation Planning</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Operation Planning[h4]
      Please see page 17 of the Desperate Allies Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="17">Desperate Allies</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>REBELBASE</Key>
    <Name>Rebel Base</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Rebel Base[h4]
      Please see page 87 of the Desperate Allies Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="87">Desperate Allies</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>CAMAR</Key>
    <Name>Camaraderie</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Camaraderie[h4]
      See page 17 of the Lead by Example Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="17">Lead by Example</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>ENEMYDEMOR</Key>
    <Name>Enemy Demoralization</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Enemy Demoralization[h4]
      See page 17 of the Lead by Example Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="17">Lead by Example</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>LOSSPREV</Key>
    <Name>Loss Prevention</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Loss Prevention[h4]
      See page 17 of the Lead by Example Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="17">Lead by Example</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>CLEARSKIES</Key>
    <Name>Clear Skies</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Clear Skies[h4]
      See page 17 of the Forged in Battle Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="17">Forged in Battle</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>MORALE</Key>
    <Name>Morale</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Morale[h4]
      See page 17 of the Forged in Battle Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="17">Forged in Battle</Source>
  </Duty>
  <Duty>
    <Key>PSYCHWAR</Key>
    <Name>Psychological Warfare</Name>
    <Description>
      [H4]Psychological Warfare[h4]
      See page 17 of the Forged in Battle Sourcebook for details.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="17">Forged in Battle</Source>
  </Duty>


</Duties>
