<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<VehActions>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>ACCDEC</Key>
    <Name>Accelerate/Decelerate</Name>
    <Description>
      The pilot may increase or decrease the ship or vehicle's
current speed by one, to a minimum of 0 or a maximum
of the ship's maximum speed rating.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="232">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="245">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="238">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>FLYDRIVE</Key>
    <Name>Fly/Drive</Name>
    <Description>
      This starship maneuver reflects the simple act of moving
the ship or vehicle closer or farther away from something
at its current speed. The number of starship maneuvers
required for a ship or vehicle to move through a given
number of range bands is dependent on its speed. It is
important to remember that range is based on the moving
ship's perspective, and is not a measure of actual
physical distance. Moving between one range band
and the next always takes two maneuvers regardless of
speed, with the following exceptions detailed below:
<ol>
  <li>
Speed 0: The ship or vehicle is not moving and cannot
use this starship maneuver until it accelerates.
  </li>
    <li>
Speed 1: One starship maneuver to move within
close range of a target or object, or two starship
maneuvers to move from close to short range or
from short range to close range.
    </li>
      <li>
Speed 2-4: One starship maneuver to move
within close range of a target or object, or to move
from close to short range or from short to close
range. Two starship maneuvers to move from close
to medium or medium to close range.
      </li>
        <li>
Speed 5-6: One starship maneuver to move
within close range of a target or object or to move
from close to medium range or from medium to
close range. Two starship maneuvers to move from
close to long or long to close range.
        </li>
</ol>
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="232">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="245">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="238">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>EVASMAN</Key>
    <Name>Evasive Maneuvers</Name>
    <Description>
      Evasive Maneuvers reflects a pilot's efforts to avoid
incoming fire, collision, or other calamity. Executing
Evasive Maneuvers upgrades the difficulty of the dice
pool once for all attacks made against the ship until
the end of the pilot's next turn. While this makes the
ship executing the starship maneuver harder to hit, it
also makes it harder for the ship executing the starship
maneuver to hit anything else. Executing Evasive
Maneuvers likewise upgrades the difficulty of the dice
pool once for all attacks made by the ship until the end
of the pilot's next turn. Evasive Maneuvers can only
be undertaken by ships or vehicles of silhouette 4 or
lower. Anything larger is typically too slow or awkward
to perform Evasive Maneuvers.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="232">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="245">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="238">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>4</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>3</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>STAY</Key>
    <Name>Stay on Target</Name>
    <Description>
      This reflects a pilot's concentration and his ability to shut
out combat-related stresses and distractions to make
sure a target is hit or an adversary destroyed. Until the
end of the pilot's next turn, all combat checks from the
vehicle or vessel executing this maneuver upgrade the
ability of the dice pool once. Unfortunately, while he is
concentrating so hard on his target, the pilot blocks out
all other threats and is an easier target for opponents.
Any combat checks made targeting a ship executing this
starship maneuver also upgrade their ability once until
the end of the pilot's next round. This starship maneuver
is restricted to small vessels like starfighters and patrol
boats; only ships or vehicles of silhouette 4 or lower can
Stay on Target.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="233">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="245">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="239">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>4</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>3</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>PUNCH</Key>
    <Name>Punch It</Name>
    <Description>
      This maneuver allows a ship or vehicle to go immediately
to its maximum speed rating from any other speed, by
throwing the throttles to maximum and overloading the
ship or vehicle's drives. While expeditious, it also puts
undue strain on a ship or vehicle. When executing this
starship maneuver, the ship or vehicle suffers one point
of system strain for every point of speed between the
ship's current speed and its maximum speed.
For example, the pilot of a YT-1300 light freighter is
hiding from an Imperial Navy patrol at speed 0 in the
lee of a large asteroid. Suddenly, he is set upon by a
pair of TIE fighters, decides that discretion is the better
part of valor, and Punches It. He immediately throws
his throttles to their maximum setting, and the ship
jumps to life. While he escapes unharmed and is able
to jump to hyperspace, the sudden acceleration causes
deals three points of strain to his ship.
This starship maneuver is restricted to ships of silhouette
4 or lower, as larger vessels have too much
mass to accelerate so quickly
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="233">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="246">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="239">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>4</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>ANGLEDEF</Key>
    <Name>Angle Deflector Shields</Name>
    <Description>
      Using this maneuver, a crewmember with access to the
shield controls can reassign up to one point of defense
from one defense zone to another. For example, a
player could shore up a vessel's forward defense zone
with a point from its aft defense zone. This maneuver
only works if the ship or vehicle has defense that can
be reassigned, as with deflector shields.<br/>
In combat involving starships or vehicles, there are
some additional actions characters may perform that
specifically apply to the ship or vehicle they are operating.
Some of these actions are labeled as Pilot Only
actions. A starship or vehicle may benefit from only
one Pilot Only action per round, no matter how many
crewmembers are aboard her. (Pilot Only actions are
actions that affect the movement of the ship itself, and
ships may only move so fast and so far.)<br/>
Remember, any of the actions listed starting on page
216 of combat can also be performed in combats involving
ships or vehicles, within the bounds of common sense.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="233">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="246">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="239">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>MECHINCPOW</Key>
    <Name>Increase Power</Name>
    <Description>Please see page 72 of the Stay on Target Sourcebook for details</Description>
    <Source Page="72">Stay on Target</Source>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaManeuver</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>3</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>BLANKBARR</Key>
    <Name>Blanket Barrage</Name>
    <Description>
      The gunner uses the ship's weapons to raise a curtain
of fire around the ship, protecting it from starfighters.
Any smaller vessel attempting an attack run will have
to brave a hurricane of heavy weaponry.<br/>
When performing the Blanket Barrage action, the
character makes an Average [DI] [DI] Gunnery check
and selects all weapons of a single type (heavy turbolasers,
medium ion cannons, etc.) within one or more
of his ship's firing arcs. Those weapons count as firing
that round. Until the end of the character's next turn,
all vehicles with silhouette 4 or smaller upgrade the
difficulty of any combat checks made against the ship
once, plus one additional time per [AD] [AD] scored on the
Blanket Barrage Gunnery check. If their combat check
generates [TH] [TH] , they suffer one automatic hit, which
deals half the base damage (rounding up) of the type
of weapon used in the Blanket Barrage action. If their
combat check generates [DE] , they suffer one automatic
hit dealing the base damage of the type of weapon used
in the Blanket Barrage action.
At the GM's discretion, the Blanket Barrage might not
cover all arcs of the ship (if the ship has no aft weaponry,
for example, it may leave an opening aft), and some
ships might be able to approach from this direction and
avoid suffering the penalties from Blanket Barrage.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="246">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>5</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>3</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>GUNN</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>CONCBARR</Key>
    <Name>Concentrated Barrage</Name>
    <Description>
      The gunner directs the vehicle's fire to focus on a precise
point on the opponent's hull. Focusing fire in this way has
the potential to deal significant damage.<br/>
When performing the Concentrated Barrage action, the
character fires all weapons of a single type (heavy turbolasers,
medium ion cannons, etc.) within a single firing
arc. This action requires at least two weapons to use, and
it cannot be used if there are not two weapons of a single
type in the chosen firing arc. Although he is firing multiple
weapons, he makes a single combat check, as per
the rules for the Performing a Combat Check with Vehicle
Weapons action. If the attack succeeds, the character
may spend [AD] once to add damage equal to the number
of weapons involved in the attack to one hit of the attack.<br/>
The Concentrated Barrage action can only be used
to target ships with a silhouette 5 or higher.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="246">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>5</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>3</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>GUNN</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>OVERBARR</Key>
    <Name>Overwhelming Barrage</Name>
    <Description>
The gunner disperses the vehicle's fire to overwhelm
the target with a multitude of shots, hitting it and every
adjoining vehicle. This tactic is often used to overwhelm
formations of enemy ships and vehicles.<br/>
When performing the Overwhelming Barrage action,
the character fires all weapons of a single type (heavy
turbolasers, medium ion cannons, etc.) within a single firing
arc. This action requires at least two weapons to use,
and cannot be used if there are not two weapons of a
single type in the chosen firing arc. Although he is firing
multiple weapons, he makes a single combat check, as
per the rules for the Performing a Combat Check with
Vehicle Weapons action. If the attack succeeds, the
character may spend O to deal one additional hit to one
vehicle that is at short range from the original target, plus
one additional vehicle for every 10 weapons involved in
the attack. Vehicles hit in this way must have a silhouette
equal to or higher than that of the original target. For
example, firing 10 weapons allows the attacker to hit two
additional targets with [AD] firing 20 weapons allows him
to hit three additional targets, and so on. The extra hit
can be triggered multiple times, but cannot target any
ships that have already been hit during this action.
These hits deal the weapon's base damage, + 1 damage
per [SU] on the check.
    </Description>
    <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>5</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>3</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>GUNN</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>DAMCONT</Key>
    <Name>Damage Control</Name>
    <Description>
      As a ship's hull shakes and rattles beneath the abuse
of an enemy's laser cannons, sparks fly and systems
begin to fail. The Damage Control action is an attempt
to mitigate such stress, whether it's caused by combat
or accident. Using this action, any Player Character
who makes a successful Mechanics check recovers one
point of system strain. The difficulty of the Mechanics
check is determined by the strain the ship is currently
suffering. Damage Control can be attempted as many
times as needed to reduce a ship's system strain to
zero (with the caveat that a single character can still
only perform one action per turn, of course).<br/>
Likewise, a skilled mechanic can even repair some of
the damage dealt to a vehicle during an ongoing fight,
although this is much trickier. In general, PCs can only
attempt one Damage Control check to reduce hull
trauma (by one point per success) per encounter—there
are only so many repairs that can be accomplished without
the facilities of a proper shipyard. In addition, the
GM is the final arbiter as to whether a Player Character
can attempt repairs of hull trauma at all (a snubfighter
pilot could not climb out of his cockpit during a dogfight
to patch his wing, nor could a speeder biker reattach one
of his control surfaces while driving through a forest).<br/>
Characters can also use this action to repair Critical
Hits the ship is suffering from. The difficulty of repairing
a Critical Hit is listed on Table 7-9: Critical Hit
Result. Checks to repair Critical Hits can be attempted
multiple times, until the Critical Hit is repaired.<br/>
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="233">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="247">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="240">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Skills>
      <Key>MECH</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>GAINADV</Key>
    <Name>Gain the Advantage</Name>
    <Description>
      This action reflects the constant, frantic give-and-take
of a dogfight between small craft like starfighters and
patrol boats or high-speed vehicles such as airspeeders.
It allows a pilot to gain the upper hand on a single opponent
so that he positions himself for a better attack during
the following round. To execute this starship action,
the pilot makes a Piloting check, the difficulty of which
is determined by the relative speeds of the ships or vehicles
involved in the attack. These difficulties are outlined
in Table 7-3: Speed Advantage Difficulty If the check
succeeds, the pilot ignores all penalties imposed by his
own and his opponent's use of the Evasive Maneuvers
starship maneuver until the end of the following round.
In addition, the pilot also chooses which defense zone
he hits with his attack. If he fails his check, he fails to
gain the advantage from the attempt and still suffers the
effects of any Evasive Maneuvers.<br/>
Once the advantage has been gained, on the following
turn the opponent may attempt to cancel out the
advantage by using Gain the Advantage as well. This
works as described earlier, but his check is one step
more difficult for each time he or his opponent has successfully
Gained the Advantage against the other.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="234">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="247">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="240">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>true</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>4</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>4</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <Skills>
      <Key>PILOTPL</Key>
      <Key>PILOTSP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>COMBAT</Key>
    <Name>Combat Check with Weapon</Name>
    <Description>
      his is similar to the Perform a Combat Check action
on page 216, with some minor differences in implementation
due to the differences between vehicles
and individuals. For this reason, the steps to perform a
combat check are repeated, with the differences written
in each step, instead of the differences being listed
without context.<br/>
Please see page 234 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook, or page 249 of the Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook, for details
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="234">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="249">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Skills>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>PLOTCOURSE</Key>
    <Name>Plot Course</Name>
    <Description>
      When aboard a vehicle in combat, those who are not
piloting or firing weapons may still want to contribute to
the encounter. Although the number of options open to
them is limited only by a player's creativity, Table 7-4:
Additional Starship and Vehicle Actions has a list of
actions passengers can attempt during encounters. The
table lists the actions by name, the skill required, the
check's attendant difficulty, and the results of a success
(GMs should modify the difficulty of the check if they see
fit, and can also keep players from using certain skills
that may not make sense in a certain situation). These
actions are all covered by the Perform a Skill Check
action, and are by no means an exhaustive list. However,
they do serve to provide a range of ideas.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>ASTRO</Key>
      <Key>PERC</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>COPILOT</Key>
    <Name>Copilot</Name>
    <Description>The crewmember serves as the vehicle's copilot, managing systems and auxiliary equipment
to allow the pilot to focus on flying or driving. On a successful check, each success
downgrades the difficulty of the pilot's next piloting check by 1</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <RequiresSpeed>true</RequiresSpeed>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>PILOTPL</Key>
      <Key>PILOTSP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>JAM</Key>
    <Name>Jamming</Name>
    <Description>The crewmember uses the vehicle's systems to jam the communications of enemy vehicles.
On a successful check, the enemy must make an Average [DI] [DI] Computers check to use
its communication systems. The difficulty increases by one for each additional # and the
jamming affects an additional target for each t> spent.</Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>COMP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>BOOSTSHIELD</Key>
    <Name>Boost Shields</Name>
    <Description>
      The crewmember reroutes power from other systems to boost the defensive systems of a
vehicle. This only works if the vehicle already has a defense rating. On a successful check, the
vehicle suffers 1 system strain and increases the defense of one defense zone by one until
the beginning of his next turn. Additional [SU] increase the duration by one round per [SU]
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>MECH</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>MANREP</Key>
    <Name>Manual Repairs</Name>
    <Description>
      In some cases, repairs can be as simple as a sturdy metal plate welded over a damaged
system. If the CM allows it and the crewmember has the proper tools for the job, the
crewmember can attempt to use the Damage Control action with Athletics rather than
Mechanics. If successful, he may remove 1 point of hull trauma from the ship, plus 1
additional point for each additional [SU] [SU] .Remember, this follows the limitations of the
Damage Control action, and thus may only be attempted once per encounter.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>ATHL</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>FIREDISC</Key>
    <Name>Fire Discipline</Name>
    <Description>
      The crewmember forgoes fighting to analyze the opponents' tactics and direct his fellows to
greater accuracy with their weapons fire. If successful, the next crewmember firing a weapon
aboard the ship can add [BO] to his check. Each additional [SU] [SU] grants this to an additional
crewmember. In addition, the crewmember may spend [AD] [AD] [AD] to allow every hit from
shipboard weapons to inflict 1 system strain on their target as well as regular damage until
the beginning of his next turn as the carefully timed shots pummel shields and overload
systems.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>DISC</Key>
      <Key>LEAD</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>SCANENEMY</Key>
    <Name>Scan the Enemy</Name>
    <Description>
      The crewmember uses the ship's scanners to study the enemy. If successful, he learns what
weapons the ship has. its modifications, and its system strain and hull trauma thresholds. If
he spends [AD] [AD] he can also learn its current system strain and hull trauma levels.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>PERC</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>SLICE</Key>
    <Name>Slice Enemy's Systems</Name>
    <Description>
      The crewmember uses powerful shipboard computers to attempt to disrupt the systems of
an enemy vehicle. If successful, he reduces the defense of one zone on the target vehicle for
one round per [SU] .A [TR] may be spent to disable a weapon system for one round, and [SU] [SU]
may be spent to inflict 1 system strain on the target vehicle.
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>COMP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>SPOOFMISS</Key>
    <Name>Spoof Missiles</Name>
    <Description>
      The crewmember tracks incoming attacks and uses vehicle systems to disrupt their tracking
systems, or even times incoming missiles and drops flares and chaff at the opportune
moment If successful, any attacks against the crewmember's ship or vehicle using weapons
with the Guided quality upgrade their difficulty by one (plus an additional upgrade for every
additional [AD] [AD] ) until the start of the crewmember's next turn
    </Description>
    <Sources>
      <Source Page="237">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="248">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
      <Source Page="241">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
    </Sources>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>COMP</Key>
      <Key>VIGIL</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>MECHWATCHBACK</Key>
    <Name>Watch Your Back!</Name>
    <Description>Please see page 73 of the Stay on Target Sourcebook for details</Description>
    <Source Page="73">Stay on Target</Source>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>COMP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
  <VehAction>
    <Key>MECHTARGETLOCK</Key>
    <Name>Target Lock</Name>
    <Description>Please see page 73 of the Stay on Target Sourcebook for details</Description>
    <Source Page="73">Stay on Target</Source>
    <ActionTypeValue>vaAction</ActionTypeValue>
    <PilotOnly>false</PilotOnly>
    <SilhLow>-1</SilhLow>
    <SilhHigh>-1</SilhHigh>
    <SpeedLow>-1</SpeedLow>
    <SpeedHigh>-1</SpeedHigh>
    <Active>true</Active>
    <VehicleOnly>true</VehicleOnly>
    <Skills>
      <Key>COMP</Key>
    </Skills>
  </VehAction>
</VehActions>
