<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Species>
  <Key>BOTH</Key>
  <Name>Bothan</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Bothans[h4]
    Masters of manipulation and collectors of data,
Bothans are known to excel both as spies and as diplomats.
Though it is perhaps unfair to universally characterize
them as untrustworthy, it is generally unwise to
forget that most Bothans are raised believing their own
interests are genuinely paramount.<br/>
Physiology: Averaging 1.5 to 1.6 meters tall, Bothans
are bipedal humanoids that, from a human's perspective,
display an interesting mix of feline, equine,
and canine traits. With multidirectional and oversized
ears, keen olfactory senses contained in their
tapered snouts, and eyes capable of a much wider
range of focus than the average humanoid, Bothans
are extremely effective at picking up the vast diversity
of information they instinctively crave. Thanks to
their diminutive stature, they are capable of getting
into places barred to human-sized (and larger) beings.
Bothans also possess a unique manner of communication
that involves rippling their fur in patterns decipherable
by other Bothans. Though capable of wearing
footgear, Bothans have hooves instead of feet, and
both males and females sport a dangling beard at the
end of their snout.<br/>
Society: Though the planet of Bothawui is officially
neutral in the conflict between the Empire and the
Alliance (and, in fact, there are plenty of Bothans who
play both sides for their personal gain), the upper echelons
of the Alliance know the galaxy-spanning Bothan
Spynet is working actively to further Alliance interests.
Nonetheless, the leadership of Bothawui plays the
game with both sides very carefully, and somehow it
works; both Alliance and Imperial intelligence operations
use the planet for clandestine purposes and keep
it out of the line of fire in the conflict.<br/>
Despite reputations for being as greedy and devious
as Hutts, Bothans are, for the most part, ethical beings.
Their ethics, however, derive from a code of behavior
they call "The Way," which teaches that the pursuit of
power and influence is right and necessary. For Bothans,
money is only a means, not an end; ultimately, the
capacity to influence matters to reflect their goals is the
prize which must be sought. Bothans may well select a
cause—a noble one, at that—to champion. They simply
prefer manipulation and scheming to gain victory for the
cause, rather than resorting to violence.<br/>
Homeworld: Bothawui is a Mid-Rim world, temperate in
climate and varied in terrain. Cosmopolitan and developed,
Bothawui is rich in natural resources, agriculture,
and industry. It is also the center of a Bothan-dominated
sector of planets.<br/>
Language: The spoken form of the Bothans' language
is Bothese, and they refer to their written tongue as
Botha. They have a third form of communication called
Wrendui, which is based solely on the rippling of their
fur. Though the base use of such ripples merely conveys
emotions, they have developed many forms of
Wrendui (which can be switched at will with the simplest
of cues) to communicate in far more complex
ways. Highly placed non-Bothans in the Bothan Spynet
are taught a few of these forms, but only a Bothan may
know all of them.<br/>
Life in the Alliance: Not surprisingly, Bothans are
both drawn to and encouraged to undertake roles
capitalizing on their capabilities with knowledge, data,
and manipulation. Diplomat and Spy are ideal career
choices for many Bothans, with Duties like Intelligence,
Counter-intelligence, and Political Support favoring
their nature. Most Alliance leaders understand that
Bothans are likely to take whatever they learn and
share it through the Spynet; these Rebels accept this
as a fair price for gaining access to that same resource.
  </Description>
  <Sources>
    <Source Page="43">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Source Page="51">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Sources>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>1</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>3</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>11</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>100</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <SkillModifiers>
    <SkillModifier>
      <Key>SW</Key>
      <RankStart>1</RankStart>
      <RankLimit>2</RankLimit>
    </SkillModifier>
  </SkillModifiers>
  <TalentModifiers>
    <TalentModifier>
      <Key>CONV</Key>
      <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
    </TalentModifier>
  </TalentModifiers>
</Species>
