<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Species>
  <Key>DROID</Key>
  <Name>Droid</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Droid[h4]
    Whereas the Empire generally treats its droids as little
more than self-directed tools and disposable assets,
the Alliance has come to value the contributions and
involvement of droids in their efforts. Droids help fill
personnel gaps across the board, especially in noncombat
roles. Astrogation, engineering, medicine, and
even piloting (when there aren't enough breathing
pilots around)—all are tasks droids readily and loyally
fulfill as part of the effort to overthrow the Empire.<br/>
Creativity is not only allowed when a player decides
to build a droid PC, it is encouraged. Droids in A C E OF
REBELLION are simply another species choice, albeit
one with a wider range of variables for the player to
manipulate. Their special abilities directly convey their
non-flesh-and-blood nature, and gear choices such as
weapons and armor can be defined as being built into
the droid's body instead of functioning as separate,
stand-alone equipment.<br/>
The personality of a droid is a more delicate matter.
The very fact that the droid is a Player Character means
that it is self-aware and independent-minded (unless
the player wants to play a character who is completely
subservient to the surrounding biologicals, of course).<br/>
Original design and function should always remain
a part of who a droid is. It may have capabilities far
beyond its initial programming, but it still maintains
predilections related to what it was created to do.
Power droids can become fully capable engineers, yet
they always pay extra attention to the power flows in
their areas of responsibility. A protocol droid might well
develop the capacity to wield arms and enter combat,
but it likely wants to explore nonviolent options first.<br/>
Physical Description: In the Star Wars universe, the
available types of droids are almost as varied as the
types of alien species, though there are some standard
models that are well known and fairly ubiquitous. Players
can choose to have forms ranging from the bipedal
and human-like to utilitarian box-like forms, animal-like
forms, or anything else they can imagine.<br/>
<h4>VARIOUS INDIVIDUAL MODELS</h4>
While an individual droid PC is likely at least somewhat
customized, there are quite a few standard models that
make a good starting place to work from.
<ol>
  <li>
2-1B Surgical Droid (Genetech/lndustrial
Automaton): The 2-1 B Surgical Droid is a highly
intelligent and flexible thinker, as one would expect
of a droid whose decisions involve life and death.
A rather ugly chassis hides a remarkably complex
and open-ended behavioral circuitry matrix, making
them ideal chief medical officers aboard most
Alliance Fleet capital ships.
  </li>
    <li>
3PO Protocol Droids (Cybot Galactica): The
3P0 series of protocol droids are some of the most
human-like automata ever developed—perfect
for their assigned tasks as ambassadors, political
aides, translators, and personal attaches. However,
their advanced SyntheTech AA-1 VerboBrains can
sometimes develop neuroses or other "quirks."
Nonetheless, many protocol droids assist Alliance
operatives, especially where recruitment and gaining
political support is concerned.
    </li>
      <li>
IG Assassin Droids (Holowan Mechanicals):
Culminating with the feared and deadly IG-88
model, the IG series is infamous for spawning some
of the most lethal assassin droids in the galaxy. IG
droids rarely meet an opponent they cannot eliminate,
but their resistance to instructions not involving
lethal termination of targets makes them difficult
to incorporate into most Alliance-developed
operations. Most IGs are in service to the Empire.
      </li>
      <li>
LE-VO Law Enforcement Droids (Rseikharhl
Droid Group): The success of the LE-VOs in deterring
crime in the Rseikharhl sector has led to their
adoption galaxy-wide as appropriate models for
police assistance and private security. Their programming
requires them to follow Imperial codes
to the letter and only use force when absolutely
necessary. Though they are hardly ever equipped
with lethal weaponry, they know how to target a
stun weapon for maximum effect. LE-VOs are only
useful to the Alliance if their initial hard-coded loyalty
to the Empire can be broken.
      </li>
      <li>
LOM Protocol Droid (Industrial Automaton):
The LOM series was Industrial Automaton's
attempt to upset a market dominated by Cybot
Galactica. IA attempted to make a protocol droid
very similar to the 3P0 units but with an insectoid
head to appeal to niche markets. However, bad
PR from at least one unit's career as a jewel thief
caused IA to scrap the line. Some of the remaining
LOM droids do have a habit of developing interesting
and unexpected personalities—including a few
who have decided that fighting as Rebels against
the Empire is a rewarding path.
      </li>
      <li>
R-Series Astromech Droids (Industrial Automaton):
The wildly successful R-series ranges from
the original and cumbersome Rl to the famous
R2 unit and all the way to the soon-to-be-released
R6. Besides the Rl (which is over two meters tall
and works primarily aboard capital ships), all of the
R-series astromechs are roughly a meter or so tall
and are designed to ride in sockets aboard snubfighters
to perform astrogation calculations, permitting
hyperspace jumps. A wide variety of tools—and
a surprising propensity for cleverness and independence
when left without a memory wipe—make them
fine repair droids and often excellent companions.
      </li>
</ol>
Society: In the wider galaxy (aside from wild rumors
about "machine planets"), most droids are mere functionaries
within societies that completely rely upon
them and expect them to obey. Within the Alliance, however,
they have come to know a higher level of respect.
Though many in the Alliance's structure still hold with
the idea of memory wipes and programming for necessary
tasks only (especially when droids are acquired
from Imperial or questionable sources), more and more
leaders and commanders have taken the long view on
allowing trusted droids to continue to develop a sense
of personal independence and purpose. On more than
one occasion, this has proven to be a brilliant strategy,
and will likely continue.<br/>
As such, many droids have transcended their programming
and original purpose to become more than
they started as, and find service in the Alliance very
satisfactory. Granted, those coming from outside regular
channels face a great deal of suspicion, which is
often impossible to overcome. Technicians usually scan
a droid's memory bank and programming thoroughly
to ensure there are no hidden commands betraying the
Rebellion in any way.<br/>
Life in the Alliance: Most droids are better suited to
non-combat roles, serving in support areas to better
enable the forces of the Rebellion to fight efficiently
and effectively. Many droids of a technical nature
serve aboard capital ships, often handling the tasks
of dozens of non-droid crew, making personnel shortages
less devastating to the Alliance Navy. Astromech
droids abound as more and more snubfighters, like the
X-wing, are brought into service.<br/>
Individual droids with their own motivations can
serve in any capacity they desire, though most choose
careers and specializations that fit their basic design
and functions. The Duty a droid chooses, as well,
should suit its chosen path.
  </Description>
  <Sources>
    <Source Page="45">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Source Page="53">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Sources>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>1</Brawn>
    <Agility>1</Agility>
    <Intellect>1</Intellect>
    <Cunning>1</Cunning>
    <Willpower>1</Willpower>
    <Presence>1</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>175</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <TalentModifiers>
    <TalentModifier>
      <Key>ENDUR</Key>
      <RankAdd>1</RankAdd>
    </TalentModifier>
  </TalentModifiers>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>DROIDAB</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>DROIDABSK</Key>
          <Name>Additional Career Skills</Name>
          <Description>May train in two additional career skills and one additional specialization skills</Description>
          <StartingSkillTraining>
            <SkillTraining>
              <SkillCount>2</SkillCount>
              <Requirement>
                <Career>true</Career>
              </Requirement>
            </SkillTraining>
            <SkillTraining>
              <SkillCount>1</SkillCount>
              <Requirement>
                <Specialization>true</Specialization>
              </Requirement>
            </SkillTraining>
          </StartingSkillTraining>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>DROIDAB2</Key>
      <Name>Droid</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>DROIDAB2OP1</Key>
          <Name>Feature</Name>
          <Description>Droids do not need to eat, sleep, or breath, and are unaffected by vacuum, toxins, and poisons.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>DROIDAB3</Key>
      <Name>Droid</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>DROIDAB3OP1</Key>
          <Name>Inorganic</Name>
          <Description>Droids do not gain benefits from bacta, stimpacks, or Medicine checks.  They must be repaired with repair patches and Mechanics checks.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>DROIDAB4</Key>
      <Name>Droid</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>DROIDAB4OP1</Key>
          <Name>Mechanical Being</Name>
          <Description>Droids cannot become Force sensitive, cannot acquire a Force Rating or Force powers, and are not affected by mind-altering Force powers.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>DROIDAB5</Key>
      <Name>Droid</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>DROIDAB5OP1</Key>
          <Name>Cybernetics</Name>
          <Description>Droids have a cybernetics implant cap of 6.</Description>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
  <SubSpeciesList>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>DROIDSUB1</Key>
      <Name>2-1B Surgical</Name>
      <Description>Please see page 45 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook, or page 53 of the Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook, for details.</Description>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>DROIDSUB2</Key>
      <Name>3P0 Protocol</Name>
      <Description>Please see page 45 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook, or page 53 of the Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook, for details.</Description>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>DROIDSUB3</Key>
      <Name>IG Assassin</Name>
      <Description>Please see page 45 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook, or page 53 of the Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook, for details.</Description>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>DROIDSUB4</Key>
      <Name>LE-V0 Law Enforcement</Name>
      <Description>Please see page 45 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook, or page 53 of the Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook, for details.</Description>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>DROIDSUB5</Key>
      <Name>LOM Protocol</Name>
      <Description>Please see page 45 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook, or page 53 of the Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook, for details.</Description>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>DROIDSUB6</Key>
      <Name>R-Series Astromech</Name>
      <Description>Please see page 45 of the Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook, or page 53 of the Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook, for details.</Description>
      <WeaponModifiers>
        <WeaponModifier>
          <Unarmed>false</Unarmed>
          <UnarmedName>Arc Welder</UnarmedName>
          <SkillKey>MELEE</SkillKey>
          <AllSkillKey />
          <Damage>3</Damage>
          <DamageAdd>0</DamageAdd>
          <Crit>0</Crit>
          <CritSub>0</CritSub>
          <RangeValue>wrEngaged</RangeValue>
          <Qualities>
            <Quality>
              <Key>STUNDAMAGE</Key>
              <Count>0</Count>
              <Index>0</Index>
              <MiscDesc />
              <DefZone />
              <VehicleWeaponUpgrades />
              <DieModifiers />
            </Quality>
          </Qualities>
        </WeaponModifier>
      </WeaponModifiers>
    </SubSpecies>
    <SubSpecies>
      <Key>DROIDSUB7</Key>
      <Name>Other Model</Name>
      <Description>Please see "Notable Features" for a description of this type of droid</Description>
    </SubSpecies>
  </SubSpeciesList>
  <NoForceAbilities>true</NoForceAbilities>
</Species>
