<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<Species>
  <Key>HUMAN</Key>
  <Name>Human</Name>
  <Description>
    [H4]Humans[h4]
    Ubiquitous and dominant, humans are found throughout
the galaxy. The Empire believes humans to be the
rightful rulers of all civilization; the Alliance feels differently,
yet most of the leadership of even this egalitarian
organization is made up of humans. They are the least
homogenous and most active species in known space.
Where they go, things happen.<br/>
Physiology: Averaging 1.8 meters in height (with
females averaging slightly shorter), humans are mammalian
bipeds with an internal biology that handles a
wide variety of oxygenated environments well. Their
mostly hairless skin spans a wide range of color from
very dark to very light; most range in the pale-tan to
dark brown colors, but there are distinctive variants,
especially among those offshoots considered nearhuman.
As omnivores, humans have a wide range of
available food sources, as well.<br/>
Society: Though the Empire would make it otherwise,
humans are far too diverse and widespread throughout
the galaxy to represent a single society. Every form of
government ever devised can be found in places where
humans choose to live, and economic and sociological
differences are just as varied. Although humans
helped advance technological developments throughout
known space, human cultures living as true primitives
exist as well. Generally, humans yearn for independence
and self-determination, yet there are countless
billions who gladly subjugate themselves under tyrannical
rule for the promise of prosperity and security.<br/>
Homeworld: Scholars continue to debate which of the
Core Worlds actually stands as the true human homeworld;
most claim it has to be Coruscant. Others are
convinced humans did not even originate in the Core,
instead coming from far away on sleeper or generation
ships long before the advent of hyperdrive technology.
Regardless, they now dominate the Core and are
spread throughout the galaxy, claiming many worlds
as their homes.<br/>
Language: Basic was originated by humans, and
with their ubiquity came the widespread use of it as
a connecting language for the entire galaxy. Numerous
human societies have variants and dialects, and
there are entire human civilizations that have distinct
languages with no connection to Basic at all.<br/>
Life in the Alliance: The inherent diversity of humans
extends to their roles, careers, specializations, and
chosen Duties with the Alliance. The only constant is
the lack of consistency where humans are concerned;
they are likely to pursue any path and have any set of
goals driving them. The unifying factor is their desire to
oppose the Empire, along with all of the other species
who resist.
  </Description>
  <Sources>
    <Source Page="48">Edge of the Empire Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Source Page="57">Age of Rebellion Core Rulebook</Source>
    <Source Page="55">Force and Destiny Core Rulebook</Source>
  </Sources>
  <StartingChars>
    <Brawn>2</Brawn>
    <Agility>2</Agility>
    <Intellect>2</Intellect>
    <Cunning>2</Cunning>
    <Willpower>2</Willpower>
    <Presence>2</Presence>
  </StartingChars>
  <StartingAttrs>
    <WoundThreshold>10</WoundThreshold>
    <StrainThreshold>10</StrainThreshold>
    <Experience>110</Experience>
  </StartingAttrs>
  <OptionChoices>
    <OptionChoice>
      <Key>HUMANAB</Key>
      <Name>Skills</Name>
      <Options>
        <Option>
          <Key>HUMANABSK</Key>
          <Name>Additional Non-Career Skills</Name>
          <Description>Humans start the game with one rank in two different non-career
          skills of their choice.</Description>
          <StartingSkillTraining>
            <SkillTraining>
              <SkillCount>2</SkillCount>
              <Requirement>
                <NonCareer>true</NonCareer>
              </Requirement>
            </SkillTraining>
          </StartingSkillTraining>
        </Option>
      </Options>
    </OptionChoice>
  </OptionChoices>
</Species>
